Come down,
Lord. [music]
Come down.
Come [singing]
down,
Lord.
Come down. [music]
Come down.
Alrighty, brothers and sisters. Before
we get started with today's lesson,
we're going to have the reading of the
law from Exodus chapter 20,
Ecclesiastes 12 and Revelations 22.
After that, we'll dive right on in
today's lesson. So, we're going to start
in Exodus 20 with verse one.
When you get that, brother, go ahead and
read.
God spake all these words, saying, I am
the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shall not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God,
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children, and to
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord would not hold him guiltless
that take his name in vain. Remember the
seventh day to keep it holy. Six days
shalt thou labor and do all thy work.
But the seventh day is the Lord thy God.
In it thou shalt not do any work. Thou
nor thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hallowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not coveret thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not coveret thy neighbor's
wife, nor his manvant, nor his
maidervant, nor his ox, nor his ass, nor
anything that is thy neighbors.
>> Thank you, brother. Let's go to our next
place. Ecclesiastes
12. Read those last two verses. 13 and
14. Go ahead and read them. Let us hear
the conclusion of the whole matter. Fear
God and keep his commandments. For this
is the whole duty of man. For God shall
bring every work with every
good evil.
>> Thank you, brother. Let's go to our last
place. Revelations 22
and let's read vers.
14.
Go ahead and read.
Blessed are they that do his
commandments that they may have right to
the tree of life and may enter in
through the gates into the city. For
without dogs and sorcerers and horongers
and murderers and idoltors and whosoever
love it and make it the lie. Thank you
brothers. Look brothers and sisters that
is the reading of the law. We read that
in every location on every day before
every lesson. Why? Because that is your
foundational key to salvation. Okay. We
thank the most high God in the name of
his son Jesus for his word and making
that salvation available to us. Okay. So
before we get started with today's
lesson, I want to say to all sons and
daughters Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob
spiritually and physically here in
Pittsburgh, California, good morning.
>> Good morning. And welcome home.
Welcome home here to the Israel of God
Bible study class where we teach the
Bible by subject and by title.
Reading for us today is Brother Ray. My
name is Brother James. for those that
don't know me. And you know what,
sisters and brothers,
this life that we live and this Bible in
our lap, it teaches us that death can
happen suddenly.
All of a sudden, it can come up on.
And when it does,
it brings an end to the opportunity to
change your standing before God. Because
once you take that breath, there's
nothing else you can do to change your
status with the most high.
Okay? And the Bible also tells us that
his return is going to be like a thief
in the night. It's going to come as a
surprise for some people. Okay?
That's why I was moved to do this lesson
titled Prepare
to Meet Your God.
prepare yourself to meet him because
sooner or later
sooner or later you going eyeball to
eyeball with it.
Okay?
So you may as well get your insurance
policy sewn up and solidified. So it
doesn't matter if death hits you
suddenly or if you die after a long term
of dealing with some issues or if the
Lord come back and sneak up on you, it
won't matter. Okay? You will be in a
good place with him. Okay?
There's this parable in the book of Luke
about the wealthy man that had the
plentif
your soul I'm taking from you tonight.
He's reminding us that we can take our
last breath today. What is your report
going to look like in his eyes? That's
what we talking about. So, we're going
to start today's lesson in the fourth
chapter of Amos. Amos chapter 4. Because
we cannot assume that we have unlimited
time to get our act together. We don't
have unlimited time.
You should handle every moment like this
is my last day to get right with the
Lord. If you handle every day like
you'll be okay.
But we deceive ourselves into thinking
we have enough time.
I can go and sin just for maybe two more
weeks, 10 more days, three more years,
then I'll come on in there. Man, your
life is a vapor.
Okay?
So, you have until yesterday to get it
together. That's how you should look at
it. I have until yesterday to get my
Okay. So, get prepared today because we
prepare for everything else. We don't
prepare for this. Amos 4, my brother.
Let's start at verse one. 4 and one. Go
ahead and read.
>> Hear this word.
>> That are in the mountain of Samaria.
>> Yes.
>> Which oppress the poor
>> which crush the needy.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Which say to their masters, bring us.
>> So, you know what? Uh go ahead and read.
>> The Lord God has sworn by his holiness
>> that lo the day shall come upon you that
he will take you away with hooks
>> and your posterity with fish.
>> Skip on down to verse 10, brother.
>> I have sent among you the pestilence
after the man of Egypt. Your young men
have I slain with the sword and have
taken away your horses.
>> And I have made the stink of your camps
to come up your nostrils.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yet have you not returned unto me the
Lord.
>> I've done all this to you, yet you still
won't return to me. Go ahead and read.
>> I have overthrown some of you
>> as God overthrew Sodom and Gomorra.
>> Yes.
>> And ye were as a fire brand out of the
burning.
>> Yet have you not returned unto me, says
the Lord.
>> The Lord say, I keep on chastising and
punishing you, putting signs all around
you that you need to get right, yet you
won't return.
Go ahead and read, brother.
>> Therefore, thus will I do unto thee, oh
Israel,
>> and because I will do this unto thee.
>> And the Lord say, and because I will do
this to you, go ahead and read.
>> Prepare to meet thy God.
>> Oh Israel,
>> oh Israel, you better prepare to meet
him.
>> You had better get ready because you can
take that last breath today, tomorrow,
next Wednesday. Okay? So you better get
ready. Hebrews chapter nine. My brother,
you don't have years to do this.
It's the uncertainty part that we have
to get that insurance around the things
that you don't know.
Okay. Hebrews chapter 9 and let's pick
it up at verse 27. Because when you die,
there's nothing else you can do.
9 and 27.
Hebrews 9 verse 27. Go ahead and read
that, brother.
>> And as it is appointed unto men once to
die.
>> It says appointed unto men once to die.
That's to go to sleep. Go ahead and
read.
>> But after this
>> Uhhuh.
>> the judgment.
>> But after that is the judgment. After
that is the judgment, sisters and
brothers. Are you prepared for that?
Can you stand there with like Paul say,
"Hey, I ran that good. There's a crown
laid up for me.
Can you say that?
So now let's go to Luke 12. We going to
start at verse 37.
Get your house in order.
Luke 12. Let's start at verse 37. Luke
12 and 37.
Luke 12 verse 37.
Prepare to meet your God.
Luke 12:37.
Go ahead and read.
>> Blessed are those servants whom the Lord
when he cometh shall find watching.
>> Verily I say unto you that he shall
guard himself.
>> Yes.
>> And make them to sit down to meet.
>> And will come forth and serve them.
>> And if he shall come in the second watch
or come in the third watch and find them
so blessed are those servants.
>> Yes. And this note that if the good man
of the house had known what hour the
thief would come, he would have watched
>> and not have suffered his house to be
broken through.
>> Because if you know what time the thief
is coming on what day and what night,
you can put some measures in place. You
can prepare yourself for the thief.
Okay? But go ahead and read, brother.
>> Be ye therefore ready also.
>> Uhhuh.
>> For the son of man cometh at an hour
when you think not.
>> Y'all see that? In an hour you think
not, he'll take that last breath from
you. Sometimes everybody in this room
knows somebody that died unsuspecting.
Car accident, natural disaster, heart
attack, straight bullet,
a fall on the curb, hit your head, huh?
You have no idea when you're going to
last. Okay? And that's why Jesus said,
"You don't know when he come." That's
another time, too. So now, let's go into
Acts chapter 6.
Acts chapter 6. Let's look at this,
brother.
Because sometimes it doesn't matter when
you die because your resume is already a
good one.
Your report is a good one.
Acts chapter 6. Let's look at this
brother.
Acts six and let's start at verse eight.
This is brother Stephan. Okay. 6 and 8.
Go ahead and read. And Stephan full of
faith and power did great wonders and
miracles among the people.
>> Then there arose certain of the
synagogue which is called the synagogue
of the libertines and the Ians and
Alexandrians and of them of Sicilia and
of Asia disputing with Stephan.
>> Go ahead.
>> And they were not able to resist the
wisdom and the spirit by which he spake.
>> Then they subored men which said, "We
have heard him speak blasphemous words
against Moses and against God."
>> So they gathered up some people to bear
false witness and lie on this brother.
Okay, go ahead and read. and they
stirred up the people and the elders and
the scribes and came upon him and caught
him and brought him to the council.
>> So they brought him to the council.
Let's go on into that seventh chapter
and see they brought him before the the
uh the council and let's see what he
said. Let's pick it up at verse one.
Seven and one. Go ahead and read.
>> Then said the high priest, are these
things so?
>> So the high priest asked Stephan, "Are
these things so that they accusing you
of?" Go ahead and read. And he said,
"Men, brethren, and fathers, hearken,
the God of glory appeared unto our
father Abraham
>> when he was in Mesopotamia before he
dwelt in." So now he went all the way
back and ran the history of Israel.
Going back to Abraham all the way down.
Okay. So now let's skip on down to verse
51. Verse 51, my brother, go ahead and
read.
>> Ye stiff neck and uncircumcised in heart
and ears. Mhm.
>> Ye do always resist the Holy Ghost.
>> Yeah.
>> As your fathers did, so do ye.
>> So he called them out on their
foolishness. He said, "You stiff naked,
uncircumcised in the heart and you
always resist the Holy Ghost." Go ahead
and read, brother.
>> Which of the prophets have not your
fathers persecuted?
>> And they have slain them which showed
before of the coming of the just ones.
>> Yes.
>> Of whom ye have been now the betrayers
and murderers.
>> Go ahead. who have received the law by
the disposition of angels and have not
kept it. You only planet that the angel
gave his word to you. That's why the
world now Israel go look in the mirror.
Okay.
>> Skip down my brother. Verse 57 and
continue.
>> Then they cried out with a loud voice
>> and stopped their ears and ran upon him
with one accord.
>> Yes.
>> And cast him out of the city and stoned
him. And the witnesses laid down their
clothes at a young man's feet whose name
was Saul.
>> Go ahead.
>> And they stoned Stephen, calling upon
God, and saying, Lord Jesus, receive my
spirit.
>> And he kneel down and cried with a loud
voice, Lord, lay not this sin to their
charge. And when he had said this, he
fell asleep.
>> He died right after he said that. Now,
let's go to Ecclesiastes 9. Now, when
Stephan left home that morning, do you
think He thought that he was going to
get killed and not see his house again
that day.
He had no idea.
But death can come like that. We don't
know.
So get that insurance policy, brothers
and sisters. Line your life up with the
word of God. Okay? Simple as that.
Ecclesiastes
chapter 9. Let's start at verse 12,
brother. Ecclesiastes 9 and verse 12. 9
and 12. Prepare to meet your God.
Okay. Prepare to meet them. Go ahead and
read. For man also knoweth not his time.
>> See, man does not know his time. Go
ahead and read.
>> As the fishes that are taken in an evil
net,
>> just like the fish that get caught in a
net, brother, sister, you don't know
your time. You don't know when you're
going to Take that last breath. Go ahead
and read.
>> And as the birds that are caught in the
snare,
>> yes.
>> So are the sons of men snared in an evil
time
>> when they follow suddenly upon them.
>> Yes. Hold on. Uh where ushers usher? Can
y'all make some room for the family
right here? Can y'all kind of slide
together please
and make some room?
So, uh, read that verse over. I'm sorry
about that, y'all. Read that verse over,
brother.
>> For man also knoweth not his time.
>> As the fishes that are taken in an evil
net.
>> Yes.
>> And as the birds that are caught in the
snare,
>> so are the sons of men snared in an evil
time
>> when it fathers suddenly upon them.
>> Y'all see that? See the son of man. See
that death can fall up on you suddenly.
When you least expect it, it can fall
upon you. And That's the whole point we
trying to make here. If you prepare
yourself to meet your God, it doesn't
matter when the thing falls on you
because your house is in order and your
report is prepared for him to look at it
in your favor. Okay? So, back up my
brother to verse eight. Read that. Let
thy garments be always white.
>> He said, "Let your garments be always
white." This means let your garments be
clean which means be righteous at all
times and it will not matter
brothers sisters. Okay, go ahead and
finish that.
>> And let thy head lack no
>> and let thy head lack no. Okay, so now
let's go into James chapter 4 because as
Solomon had this thing written, hey, you
don't know your time
and that you don't know your time. That
should make you reason it out even more
that you need to get your house in
order.
We all know somebody that the last time
we saw him, everything was fine. Last
time we saw him, everything was good.
Okay. And then you get that phone call
and they say, "Man, guess what? Such and
such died."
We had a brother up in Riverdale leave
the one day last year driving home
and died.
You never know, brothers and sisters.
You just never know. James 4 verse 13.
Go ahead and read that.
Go to now.
>> He that say or tomorrow we will to such
a city
>> and consume there and continue there a
year and buy and sell and get gain.
>> Y'all see that? So, some of us will say,
"You know what, man? Like, uh maybe next
year for the next three years, I'm going
to do this, man. What do you know, man,
about the next three years?" Huh? Go
ahead and read, brother.
>> Whereas you know not what shall be on
tomorrow.
>> He said, "Because you don't know what's
going to happen tomorrow." Go ahead,
brother.
>> For what is your life?
>> Is it even a vap? vapor
>> that appears for a little time and then
vanishes away.
>> Y'all know what the word vanish means?
It means to suddenly disappear. Your
life can be just like that.
Go ahead and read, brother.
>> For that ye ought to say.
>> And for that reason, this is how you
ought to word it. Go ahead, brother.
>> If the Lord will,
>> if the Lord will,
>> we shall live
>> and do this or that.
>> If the Lord will, I'll do this and I'll
do that. Just like y'all know, every
time we close out on the uh on the
Wednesday night zoom and on the Friday
night show, I say if the Lord say the
same, we'll be right back here next
week. Same time, same channel. If the
Lord say that because he can make some
changes to that. Okay. What verse was
that, brother?
>> That was the end of 15.
>> That was the end of 15. Read one more
verse for me. Go ahead and read that.
>> But now ye rejoice in your boasting.
>> All such rejoicing is evil. Do y'all see
that? He said, "So if you rejoice in
your boasting, trying to tell me about
your next 10 year plan," he said, "Hey,
that rejoicing
because you don't know what's going to
happen tomorrow, next week in November
in what they call 2027."
You can say, "Hey, if the Lord allow it,
I'll come and do this and that."
Because he can change all of that.
Brothers and sisters, let's go into
Proverbs uh uh chapter 27. We just want
that one verse. Proverbs 27 and verse
one.
Proverbs 27 and verse one, my brother.
27 and one. James said, "Your life is
but a vapor and it can vanish." So, are
you prepared?
Are you
you prepare yourself to go to the M
comedy show
>> at the Fox Theater. Huh?
You prepare to go to the concert. You
prepare the kids to go back to school
toward the end of the summer.
You prepare to get that driver's license
picture taken, don't we, sisters?
>> You hit the stylist up and after you see
the stylist, then you go take that
picture for the driver's license. You
prepare for everything. But you got to
prepare yourself to go high with the
most high God, the creator of
everything. You got to prepare yourself.
Proverbs 27 and1. Brother, go ahead and
read that. Bo not thyself of tomorrow.
>> For thou knowest not what a day may
bring forth.
>> So we got we got all of these telling us
the same thing. Don't you boast yourself
because you don't know what it may
bring. So let's go to first 25 and look
at this brother because we saw Stephan
Stefan died suddenly but his house was
in order though he was a righteous
brother.
As I said in the monologue before the
lesson we cannot assume uh brothers and
sisters that we have unlimited time to
get our act together. We can't assume
that. We must prepare for for when that
decisive moment comes down on you
because that moment could come
and it could happen when you least
expect it to happen. Okay? First Samuel
25. We all are familiar with this story
right here. But let's look at another
side of it. 1st Samuel 25 and verse 9.
This is when David sent his men to Nabal
and said, "Hey Nabal, can we get some
some food off your table to eat since we
since we uh protected your flock out
there in the field near your your your
livestock?" And let's see how Nabal
responded to that. 1st Samuel 25:9. Go
ahead and read, brother.
>> And when David's young men came,
>> they spake to Nabal according to all
those words in the name of David.
>> Uhhuh. And they answered David's
servants and said, "Who is David? And
who is the son of Jesse?"
>> Huh? Do y'all see that?
>> He said, "Who is David?" Man, you know
who David is.
>> The one that slayed 10,000 people, man.
That guy. Go ahead and read.
>> There be many servants nowadays that
break away every man from his master.
>> Skip down to 13 and read that. And David
said unto his men,
>> "G on every man his sword."
>> And they girded on every man his
>> sword.
>> When they brought that word back to
David, say, "Everybody put on your
armor. Get your sword. We about to go
clean up house over there." Go ahead and
read.
>> And David also ged on his sword.
>> And there went up after David about 400
men
>> and 200 abode by the stone. So David
took 400 men down to this man's farm.
Skip down to verse 32. Because his wife
got the word, she prepared some stuff
for David and kept David from coming
down there wiping out that man's farm.
Okay. Verse 32, brother. Go ahead and
read that.
>> And David said to Abigail, "Blessed be
the Lord God of Israel, which sent thee
this day to meet me."
>> Yeah. and blessed be thy advice and
blessed be thou
>> which has kept me this day from coming
to shed blood.
>> So David say blessed because you kept me
from coming to shed blood on this very
day. Go ahead brother
>> and from and from avenging myself with
mine own hand.
>> Go ahead.
>> For in very deed as the Lord God of
Israel liveth which hath kept me back
from hurting thee
>> except thou hast hasted and come to meet
me. Surely there had not been left until
Nabal by the morning light any that
pissed against the wall.
>> David said I wasn't going to leave one
animal breathing not even a little cat.
Nothing was going to be but the Lord
kept me from doing that and you be
blessed for that sister. Okay. So skip
on down to verse 36 and continue
brother.
>> And Abigail came to and behold he held a
feast in his house.
>> He held a what?
>> A feast. This man's having a feast.
He should have been shaking in his bones
for that message he sent back to David,
but he's having a feast out there. Go
ahead and read.
>> Like the feast of a king.
>> Like the feast of a king. Go ahead.
>> And Neabbar's heart was married within
him
>> for he was very drinking.
>> He was turning up in there. Huh? That's
what they call it today. He was turning
up, not worried about anything. But go
ahead and read. He was he was in the
house of merc.
Okay. and living in a place of pleasure
and good time and enjoying yourself. Go
ahead and read, brother.
>> Wherefore she told him nothing less or
more until the morning light.
>> Go ahead.
>> But it came to pass in the morning when
the wine was gone out of Nabal. And his
wife had told him these things. So once
that wine wore off of them, she told
him, "Hey, David brought 400 men down
here and I had to take them 200 cakes,
dress up some lamb, and do all this
other stuff because he was coming to
wipe us out." Go ahead and read.
>> Then his heart died within him.
>> His heart died within him. Go ahead.
>> And he became as a stone.
>> Go ahead, brother.
>> And it came to pass about 10 days after
>> that the Lord smoked Nabal that he died.
>> Y'all see that?
brother like it was like he went in a
coma for about 10 days still couldn't
couldn't say nothing what you going to
do when your brain ain't working right
how you going to repent how you going to
ask the Lord to forgive you for anything
because when you draw that last breath
all your opportunities to change your
status are gone
but see unlike Stephan this brother his
house was in
Stephan's house was ins
When that last breath come up on you,
what is your report going to look like?
How is the Lord going to look at your
resume when you go eyeball to eyeball
with him? Are you going to be ashamed or
are you going to be confident that you
did what he told you to do? That's the
question.
So now let's go back to Ecclesiastes
chapter 7. Yeah, he was partying and
turning up and having a good time. But I
want y'all to see something that Solomon
had written right here.
Ecclesiastes 7 and verse two. He was in
the house of merch over there
partying and eating and drinking. They
said he had the feast of a king. Huh?
Ecclesiastes
verse two. Seven and two. Go ahead and
read. It is better to go to the house of
mourning than to go to the house of
feasting.
>> Read that one more time, brother Ray.
>> It is better to go to the house of
mourning
>> than to go to the house of feasting.
>> Do y'all see that? That's like saying
it's better for you to go to a funeral
than to go to a party. Do y'all SEE
THAT? DO Y'ALL SEE THAT? Do you
understand why that is? Go ahead and
read, brother.
>> For that is the end of all men.
>> Yes. and the living will lay it to his
heart. So because at that funeral, you
got some food for thought. You got
something to think about.
You have something to consider.
But when you partying have a good time,
what are you considering? Huh? Am I too
drunk to drive home? Huh?
>> But see, when you in that house of
morning, there's some stuff on your
mind. And that morning could be for a
number of reasons.
Mama could be sick.
Child could have been in an accident.
You at that hospital
called fire.
Anything could happen. When the moments
of morning, it puts something on your
mind. It make you reconsider what you're
doing. It makes you think about, am I
okay? When the Lord looking at me,
that's what the house of morning make
you do. It'll make you consider some
things. Brother, can we just start that
verse?
and read it all the way through without
me interrupting you, brother. Verse two,
go ahead and read.
>> It is better to go to the house of
mourning
>> than to go to the house of feasting,
>> for that is the end of all men,
>> and the living will lay it to his heart.
>> Go ahead and read, brother.
>> Sorrow is better than laughter.
>> Y'all better take that one home with
you, too. Sorrow is better than
laughter. Sorrow is better than
laughter. Go ahead and read, brother.
For by the sadness of the countenance,
>> the heart is made better.
>> By that sadness, your heart is made
better. Your mind is made.
When that drum will fall on you, go
ahead and read. The heart of the wise is
in the house of morning.
>> See these verses, we got to take these
home with us, y'all. It says, "The heart
of the wise is in the house of
mourning."
The wise mind is in there because
something is on your mind.
You considering some things that you
looking at
the heart of the wise in the house of
mourning. Go ahead and read, brother.
But the heart of fools is in the house
of mercy. Y'all see that? But the heart
of fools is in the house of mercy just
like Nabal. His name means fool. He was
in there feasting for no reason. He
should have been shaking in his bones
because he should have known David was
gonna get that message and he was gonna
come over there
and spill some blood. But this verse,
these verses tell us
that morning is good for
the marrow of your bones. Let's go to
Hebrews 5. Pick it up at verse eight.
Hebrews 5. Let's pick it up at verse
eight. It is better to dwell in a house
of mourning than in a house of feasting.
I know somebody said, "Man, how does
that make sense?"
Okay,
you get enough drama fall in your life,
you hard, maybe I need to fix something.
Maybe I need to make some change. Maybe
I need to make some adjustments.
Hebrews 5. Because that drummer teach
five and eight, my
Okay. Hebrews
5 and 8. Go ahead and read.
Though he were a son, yet learned
obedience by the things which he
suffered.
>> Do y'all see that? We talking Jesus
Christ, the anointed one. It says he
learned obedience by what, brother Ray?
>> By the things which he suffered. See,
when you suffer, you learn from that.
But if it's party, party, good time,
good time, good time, get the bag, get
the bag, get the bag. Huh? What are you
learning?
Go ahead and read.
>> And being made perfect,
>> he became the author of eternal
salvation
>> and to all them that obey him. And when
we say obey him, we not talking about
when you get ready, when it's conven
hard, but you got to try, brothers and
sisters. Let's go to Revelation chapter
22. Revelations 22. You might want to
leave your marker right there in
Revelation. We going to come back in
here about six or seven more times in
Revelation. Okay. Revelation 22 and 7.
Let's pick up some of these red words in
Revelation. Okay, some of these red
letter words. Revelations chapter 22,
let's start at verse 7. Prepare to meet
your maker, sisters and brothers.
Prepare to meet them.
22 and 7. Go ahead and read. Behold, I
come quickly.
>> Blessed is he that keepeth the sayings
of the prophecy of this book.
>> The book say, "Blessed is the one that
keep the prophecy of this book."
You are blessed if you do that. Skip
down to verse 11, my brother. Go ahead
and read that.
>> He that is unjust, let him be unjust
still.
>> Because however the Lord catch you,
that's what it is. However he catch you,
that's what it is. He say he that is
unjust, let him be unjust still. Go
ahead and read.
>> And he which is filthy,
>> let him be filthy still.
>> And if you filthy, then hey, that's how
you got called. Then let you be filthy
still. Go ahead and read. And he that is
righteous,
>> let him be righteous still.
>> And if you righteous, that's how the
Lord caught you. Then you going to get
your reward for your righteousness. Go
ahead, brother.
>> And he that is holy, let him be holy
still.
>> So y'all see that? However the Lord
catch you, however you get caught,
however you get caught, that's what it
is. Go ahead and read.
>> And behold,
>> I come quickly.
>> And he said he's coming quickly like a
thief in the night. Go ahead and read.
and my reward is with me to give every
man according as his work shall be.
Everybody going to get rewarded
according to their works. It is as
simple as that. Okay. So now let's go
into uh Ezekiel 18 because in that
Revelations 22 and 11 he said if you
unjust then you're unjust. If you're
filthy is that if you're righteous is
that? Holy is that ain't nowhere in that
verse did it say well if God know your
heart he know your heart
>> because that's what people use to do
those unrighteous things well you know
what God know my art
you right you right
you dead right he does know it and I'mma
tell y'all something people are blind to
this Bible
I was in
Thursday
picking up the meat for the
old brother sitting in the car asking
how much it cost to charge my car and I
walked over that tour and then which
made me late bringing the food up here
cuz I spent an hour with that brother.
He had a great Bible on his dashboard.
An hour with that brother.
He acknowledged everything that we read
out of his book was the truth, but I
can't leave that Sunday church.
Then the brother said, "I'm going to
heaven though." I said, "What?" I was on
my way leaving. I turned back around and
reached in the car, grabbed his Bible,
read that John 3 right there. What Jesus
say right there, brother? No man has
ever died and ascended up to heaven.
Who teaching you that, brother?
There's a spiritual battle going on,
y'all. You can show people in their own
Bible. They can read it to you, but they
are not going to leave that church over
there. They're not leaving.
Brother had me late getting out here.
And by the way, that's the only thing
that make me late for anything. Take
care of God's business.
But you got people late for God's
business for SOME WORLDLY STUFF.
MAKE THAT MAKE SOME SENSE.
HUH?
You late for God's business cuz you
taking care of some worldly business.
Shame on you.
You can't read in that Revelations 221
that if he catch you convenient and part
time go
there's no middle ground in there. He
said you either filthy or you right. You
either holy or you unjust. There ain't
no middle ground. We got to get away
from thinking there's some sometime
almost lukewarm middle ground with the
Lord. You either in or you out. YOU
EITHER HOT OR YOU COLD.
Y'all got to stop making him a clean cuz
that is not He's a lion of Judah.
I know y'all watch Animal Channel.
When that male lion catch a little baby,
no sympathy at all.
When the Lord come back like that,
however he catch you, that's how you
going to be judged.
Ezekiel 18, let's go and put something
on that. Ezekiel 18, let's put something
on that one. Ezekiel chapter 18.
However the Lord catch you,
what have you done for me lately?
Ezekiel 18 and 26, my brother. and 26.
Go ahead and read.
>> When a righteous man turneth away from
his righteousness,
>> Uhhuh.
>> and committh iniquity and dieth in them.
>> Do y'all see that? So when a righteous
man turn from that righteousness and
start living a sinful life or just
commit a sin and then he die in that sin
and he dies inside that sin. Go ahead
and read, brother.
>> For this iniquity that he hath done
shall he die.
>> And we ain't talking the first death,
the sleeping death. You talking about
that second death. Back up and read that
verse 24, brother. Go ahead and read
that.
>> But when the righteous turneth away from
his righteousness
>> and committeth iniquity
>> and doeth according to all the
abominations that the wicked man doeth,
>> shall he live?
>> That's the question. Shall he live? Go
ahead and read.
>> All his righteousness that he hath done
shall NOT BE MENTIONED.
>> ALL THEM 56 years of righteousness that
you had won't even be mentioned. You got
caught in that sin, man. You got caught
in it. Prepare to meet your God,
brothers and sisters, because however he
catch you, that's it.
>> Go ahead and read, brother.
>> In his trespass, that he have
trespassed.
>> Yes.
>> And in his sin that he hath sinned, in
them shall he die.
>> So we are reading this, brothers and
sisters. Why don't you go ahead and get
your insurance policy lined up with the
Lord?
Clean up your garments before him.
Sisters and brothers, let's go to
Leviticus 26. Let's look at something.
Leviticus 26.
Leviticus chapter 26. Let's start at
verse one.
Leviticus 26. You may as well.
All them other things you tried,
how did they work for you?
Leviticus 26
and verse one. 26 and verse one. Go
ahead and read that, brother.
>> Ye shall make you no idols, nor grave in
image.
>> Neither rear you up a standing image.
>> Neither shall ye set up any image of
stone in your land.
>> That's right.
>> To bow down into it, for I am the Lord
your God.
>> Hey, you can't make a god with your own
hands and bow down to it. You can't do
that. That's not God. Something you made
when he made you. What else he say,
brother?
>> Ye shall keep my Sabbath.
>> You shall do what?
>> Keep my Sabbath.
>> Go ahead, brother.
>> And reverence my sanctuary.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I am the Lord.
>> He said, you shall keep my Sabbath. Go
ahead and read.
>> If you walk in my statutes and keep my
commandments and do them,
>> then I will give you rain and do.
>> So now there's that big word if. He
said, "Now if you walk in my statutes
and keep my commandments and do them, if
you do that, if you do that, if you do
that, now if Go ahead and read,
>> "And the land shall yield her increase."
>> Your land shall yield her increases. Go
ahead.
>> And the trees of the of the field shall
yield their fruit.
>> He said, "And your trees shall yield
their fruit." Skip down to verse nine
and read that. See what else he said.
>> For I will have respect unto you.
>> Wait a minute.
The Lord said he will have respect unto
you if you keep his commandments. Did we
just read that? WHAT IF YOU DON'T KEEP
THEM? Does he respect you then?
>> Huh?
Go ahead and start that verse over,
brothers. Verse nine. Go ahead and read
that.
>> For I will have respect unto you.
>> Yes.
>> And make you fruitful
>> and multiply you and establish my
covenant with you.
>> This is stuff is in black and white.
Let's go to to the the fifth chapter of
let's back up one chapter. The Lord said
he will have respect unto you. He said
keep those commandments, keep those
statues. He say keep that Sabbath day.
Okay.
Leviticus 25 and1. Let's show y'all
something about how important this
Sabbath day is because he said your land
should have a Sabbath day. That's right.
The dirt, the soil that you plant in is
supposed to have a Sabbath. Go ahead and
read that, brother. And the Lord spake
unto Moses and Mount Si, saying
>> yes,
>> speak unto the children of Israel, and
say unto them,
>> when you come into the land which I give
you, then shall the land keep a Sabbath
unto the Lord.
>> Go ahead.
>> Six years thou shalt sew thy field.
>> He said, six years you going to sew
those fields. Go ahead.
>> And six years thou shalt prune thy
>> and gather in the fruit thereof.
>> Go ahead. But in the seventh year shall
be a Sabbath of rest unto the land,
>> a Sabbath for the Lord.
>> Thou shalt neither sow thy field nor
prune thy vineyard.
>> So do we see this so far? Now he said on
the seventh year, you can't plant in the
field. And whatever grow on his own, you
can't touch it. So if some grapes happen
to grow, let them fall to the earth.
Some corn happen to grow, let them fall.
The earth know what to do with that
stuff. It's going to rejuvenate itself
with it. Okay, that way you don't have
to put chemicals on there to fertilize
your food. The earth is going to take
care of itself.
The earth will take care of itself. So
the Lord say, hey, he said,
uh, thou shalt neither sew the field nor
prune it.
Not, well, I'mma just go out here and
prune in one corner. No, he say you
can't touch the food.
We got to stop making allowances to go
against the word of God, brothers and
sisters. That's what we got to stop.
Skip down, my brother, to that verse 20.
Read that.
>> Oh, yeah. Go ahead and read that five.
That which groweth of its own accord
>> of thy harvest, thou shalt not reap.
>> See, that's what we just said. If
something still grow on its own, you
can't even harvest that. Go ahead and
read.
>> Neither gather the grapes of thy vine
unressed.
>> Why is that, brother? It is a year of
rest to the land.
>> You can't do it because it's a year of
rest to the land. So you can't touch the
food. Okay. So now skip down to verse 20
and continue.
>> And if he shall say, "What shall we eat
the seven years?"
>> Because you know somebody going to ask
that question. What we going to eat
then?
What's the answer, brother? Go ahead and
read.
>> Behold, we shall not sow nor gather in
our increase. Mhm.
>> Then I will command my blessing upon you
in the six years.
>> So if you obedient to that, the Lord
said, I will command my blessing upon
you in that year number six. How is
that, brother? Go ahead and read.
>> And it shall bring forth fruit for three
years.
>> It's going to bring you crop for three
years on that sixth year. Do y'all see
that?
>> But see, it just goes to show that if
you handle the Sabbath right, the Lord
will bless you right.
He will bless you. But you got to handle
that Sabbath day right. You can't do it
according to what's convened for you or
what you think in your mind. If if you
think it's right, then read it to
yourself out the book. If you think it's
right, just go read it to yourself. Then
it's okay.
I'm telling you now. Don't come ask me
cuz I'mma tell you real. I wouldn't do
that.
He said it'll give you fruit for three
years just taking that one year off. Go
ahead and read, brother.
>> And ye shall sow the eighth year.
>> You're going to sew on that eighth year.
Go ahead.
>> And eat yet of old fruit.
>> You going to still eat that old fruit in
year number eight that grew in year six.
Go ahead and read, brother.
>> Until the ninth year.
>> Until the ninth year. Go ahead.
>> Until her fruits come in.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Ye shall eat of the old store. Until
them fruits come in at night, you going
to eat the old store. You going to need
six, seven, and eight
from year number six because you going
to oy and let that land rejuvenate
itself and rest itself and then you
receive your blessing from your
obedience
because the Lord will have respect until
what you do. It is all that simple.
Hebrews 10 verse 26 my brother. Hebrews
10 and 26.
You got to prepare yourself to meet your
God.
Because if you got your little BFF and
your cheerleader crew and you woring
about pleasing them, I'm telling you,
they can't save you. Huh? They can't
save you.
The cheerleader cannot save you from the
high God.
>> Hebrews 10 and verse 26, my brother 10
and 26. Go ahead and read.
>> For if we sin willfully,
>> sin how?
>> Willfully.
>> That means you know you sin, right?
>> Go ahead and read.
>> After that, we have received the
knowledge of the truth. After you have
received the knowledge of the truth, if
you go ahead and still sin willfully, go
ahead and read, brother.
>> There remain no more sacrifice for sins.
>> Jesus ain't going to come and die for
you no more. You can't take the the
goat, the calf, the sheep, or nothing
else down to the sacrifice for you. So
if Jesus ain't going to sacrifice
himself anymore, and you can't sacrifice
the animals anymore, then what is your
sacrifice? Who is your sacrifice? You
your own sacrifice. You going to be your
own sacrifice if you say it will.
Go ahead and read, brother.
>> But a certain fearful look looking for
of judgment.
>> That's right.
>> And fiery indignation.
>> See, we talking about certain it say a
certain looking of judgment and fiery
indignation. Go ahead and read, brother.
>> Which shall devour the adversary.
>> Go ahead.
>> He that despised Moses law died without
mercy under two or three witnesses. Go
ahead.
>> Of how much sore punishment suppose ye
shall he shall he be thought worthy who
have trotten underfoot the son of God.
>> So how much how much worth do you think
is going to be on on you who tried
underfoot the son of God? You have tried
underfoot the Christ. Go ahead and read.
>> And have counted the blood of the
covenant wherewith he was sanctified and
unholy things. And you have counted the
blood of the covenant an unholy thing.
Why? Because you have willfully sinned
against him. He opened the door for you
to get salvation. And you saying, you
know what, skip that. I'm going to do
what I want to do. Why? Because the Lord
know my heart.
Go ahead and read. And have done despite
>> unto the spirit of grace.
>> And you have done despite unto the
spirit of grace. And you have counted
that blood
an unholy thing. Skip down to verse 38
and continue, brother.
>> Now the just shall live by faith.
>> He said, "The just shall live by faith."
Go ahead.
>> But if any man draw back,
>> my soul shall have no pleasure in you.
>> Now the Lord is talking. He said, "You
draw back, my soul will have no pleasure
in you. No respect either." Go ahead and
read.
>> But we are not of them who draw back
unto predition.
>> Uhhuh.
>> But of them that believe to the saving
of the soul.
>> I know that's right, brother. So, let's
stay in Hebrews. Let's go into that 12th
chapter. Pick it up at verse 6. Hebrews
12 and 6. Prepare to meet your God.
Prepare to go eyeball to eyeball with
him. You got to get yourself ready
because nobody's going to stand in line
with you. It's going to be you and him
one on one with your resume, your
report, your folder sitting right there.
In fact, let's just watch the video.
Okay.
Hebrews 12 and 6. Go ahead and read.
>> For whom the Lord loveth,
>> he chastenth.
>> Yes.
>> And scorges every son whom he receiveth.
>> See, if you belong to the Lord and you
cut out a line, yeah, he'll he'll
chastise you a little bit. He'll drop a
little drum on you to get you straight.
Go ahead and read.
>> If you endure chastity, God deals with
you as with sons. You can handle it.
He'll He'll deal with you like you want
to hear, like any man would deal with
his son. Go ahead and read.
>> But what son is he whom the father
chastenth not?
>> You show me a father that won't chastise
his son for doing something wrong. Go
ahead and read.
>> But if he be without chastisement,
>> but however, if there's no chastisement
for you for operating outside the word
of God, go ahead and read.
>> Whereof all are partakers.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Then are ye bastards.
>> Then are ye bastards. Go ahead.
>> And not sons.
So y'all see some people getting away
with murder.
They don't belong to God. He ain't got
no punishment. Just let him go do what
he going to do
and we'll get him at the end.
>> What verse is that, brother? Verse
eight.
>> Verse eight.
>> Go ahead and read one more.
>> Furthermore,
>> we have had fathers of our flesh which
corrected us.
>> Yes.
>> And we gave them reverence. He said,
"Listen, your your your natural dad
chastise you and punish you and give you
instruction and you give him." Go ahead
and read.
>> Shall we not much rather be in
subjection unto the father of spirits
and live?
>> He said, "So shouldn't we much rather be
in the spirit?
Shouldn't we do more for him?"
>> Should we?
>> So now let's go into Romans 13. Romans
13.
Romans chapter 13.
Look what Paul's about to say right
here.
Romans 13
and let's start at verse 11. Romans 13
and verse 11. 13 and 11.
Romans chapter 13. And again today's
title is prepare to meet your God.
Romans 13 and 11. Go ahead and read it,
brother.
>> And that knowing the time that now it is
high time to awake out of sleep.
>> So Paul is saying it is high time. It is
right now time to wake up out of that
sleep. Go ahead and read.
>> For now is our salvation nearer than
when we believe.
>> See, the salvation is nearer than when
we believe.
>> Go ahead.
>> The night is far.
>> The day is at hand.
>> Yes.
>> Let us therefor Cast off the works of
darkness.
>> Yes.
>> And let us put on the armor of light.
>> Go ahead.
>> Let us walk honestly as in the day
>> and not in rioting and drunkenness, not
in chambering and wants, not in strife
and envy.
>> Go ahead.
>> But put ye on the Lord Jesus Christ.
>> You better put on the Lord Jesus Christ.
Go ahead.
>> And make no provision for the flesh
>> to fulfill the lust thereof.
>> See that? That part right there. He
said, "Make not provision for the flesh
to fulfill the love thereof." Because
your flesh can talk you into
your flesh can talk you into doing
something that you shouldn't do. And
right after you do it, you feel real bad
about it. But you've done it already.
Huh? So now let's go to Revelation
chapter 3. Revelations 3. We just want
one verse. Verse three. Revelations 3
and three. Keep your mark in Revelation.
We going to be jumping in and out.
Revelations 3 and 3.
3 and 3.
Revelations 3 and verse three.
We read earlier in the lesson that that
death can come upon you at any moment
that you don't know. The return of the
Lord God can come upon you just like
that as well. Revelations 3 and 3. Go
ahead and read.
>> Remember therefore how thou hast
received and heard and hold fast and
repent.
>> Yes.
>> If therefore thou shalt not watch,
>> I will come on thee as a thief.
>> He said if you're not watching, I will
come on you as a thief. Go ahead and
read.
>> And thou shalt not know what hour I will
come upon thee.
>> And you won't know what hour he's
coming. Just like you don't know what
hour you going to take that last breath.
You have no idea when that is. Brothers
and sisters, let's go into First
Thessalonians. Chapter 5.
First Thessalonians 5 and pick it up at
verse two. First Thessalonians 5 and
two. He said he's going to come like a
thief.
First Thessalonians 5 and two.
5 and two.
First Thessalonians
5 and verse two.
Go ahead and read it, brother. Forel,
for yourselves know perfectly
>> that the day of the Lord so cometh as a
thief in the night.
>> Yes, sir.
>> For when they shall say peace and
safety,
>> then sudden destruction cometh upon
them.
>> He said people going to be saying, "Hey,
man. There's a lot of safety out here.
There's some peace out here. But then
sudden destruction come." Go ahead and
read
>> as travail upon a woman with child. And
they shall not escape. and they shall
not escape because of that sudden
destruction. Go ahead and read.
>> But ye, brethren,
>> are not in darkness.
>> That that day should overtake you as a
thief.
>> So Paul is talking to the saints. He
said that day shouldn't come as a thief
to you because you already know what to
look for. You have been told and taught
the signs of the end times. Like we look
at things right now that's going on in
Europe and over there in the land of
Isra
And we can see things coming. We can see
the political stuff with Russia and
China.
So it shouldn't come up on you like a
thief. And really at the end of the day,
it shouldn't matter if it does or not.
It won't matter.
>> Okay. Go ahead and read, brother.
>> Ye are all the children of light.
>> Yes.
>> And the children of the day. Mhm.
>> We are not of the night, nor of
darkness.
>> Go ahead.
>> Therefore, let us not sleep as do
others, but let us watch and be sober.
>> He said, let us watch and be sober. Go
ahead.
>> For they that sleep in the night.
>> And they that be drunken are drunken in
the night.
>> Go ahead.
>> But let us who are of the day be sober.
>> Yes.
>> Putting on the breast breastplate of
faith and love,
>> and for in the hope of salvation. Yes.
Let's go to Revelation 16 because when
that sudden destruction comes, there is
no escape, brothers and sisters. That's
where you That's why you may well just
have everything in order right now. If
it's not in order, get it in order
yesterday. Okay?
Revelations 16 and 15.
It's like that parable of those 10
virgins. Five of them had oil for the
lamps and five didn't. And the five that
didn't, they went and knocked on the
door.
And the master said, "Hey, I don't even
know you. I know you not cuz they didn't
prepare."
Revelation 16, one verse, verse 15. What
that say, brother?
>> Behold,
>> I come as a thief.
>> It is the Lord talking now. Behold, I
come as a thief. Go ahead.
>> Blessed is he that watches.
>> Blessed is the that is watching
>> and keepeth his garments.
>> And the ones that keep his garments,
>> lest he walk naked
>> and they see his shame because your
garments ain't clean. You're going to be
shamed before the Lord.
So now let's go into uh Zechariah
chapter 3.
He said he said, "Blessed is the one
that is watching and blessed is the one
that keep his or her garments." Okay. be
blessed if you keep those garments.
Keep them clean.
So, we have to understand some of this
terminology that's used in this Bible.
Blessed is he that keepeth his garments,
not your Gucci sweater.
We talking about your righteousness.
That's what we're talking about.
Zechariah 3 and one, my brother. Three
and one. Go ahead and read it.
>> And he showed me Joshua the high priest
>> standing before the angel of the Lord.
>> Yeah.
>> And Satan standing at his right hand to
resist him.
>> And the Lord said unto Satan, the Lord
rebuked thee, oh Satan, even the Lord
that hath chosen Jerusalem rebuke thee.
Is not this a brand plucked out of the
fire?
>> Now Joshua was clothed with 50 garments
and stood before the angels. We been
Keep your garments and keep them clean.
This brother Joshua got on some filthy
garments. We need to make sure we know
what that is. Go ahead and read,
brother.
>> And he answered and spake unto those
that stood before him, saying,
>> "Take away the filthy garments from him.
>> Take those filthy garments from that,
brother. Go ahead."
>> And unto him he said, "Behold, I have
caused thine iniquity to pass from thee,
>> and I will clothe thee with chains of
raignment."
>> He said, "I'mma clothe thee with change.
They took the filthy garment and caused
his iniquity to pass from away from him.
Okay, that means he's clean now, right?
Go ahead and read, brother.
>> And I said, let them set a fair mit upon
his head.
>> Yes.
>> So they set a fair mit upon his head and
clothed him with garments
>> and the angel of the Lord stood by.
>> So we see that those clean garments is
righteousness. But we got to make sure
we understand that. Let's go into
Revelation chapter 7. Revelation 7 and
start at verse 9.
They took those filthy garments off the
brother and put some clean ones on them.
Okay? So when the Lord say he come as a
thief and blessed are those that keep
their garments, he's talking about
remaining righteous, like not living a
righteous life and then all of a sudden
you got to go do something that's anti-
good or anti keeping commandments. You
don't want to get caught like that,
brothers and sisters.
Revelation
7 and verse 9. 7 and N. Go ahead and
read. After this, I beheld, and lo, a
great multitude, which no man could
number of all nations and kindreds and
people and tongues stood before the
throne and before the Lamb, clothed with
white robes and palms in their hands.
>> It said, "These people stood before the
Lamb of God.
with white robe and palm in their hands.
Go ahead and read.
>> And cried with a loud voice, saying,
"Salvation to our God which siteth upon
the throne and unto the lamb."
>> Skip down, brother, to verse 13 and
continue.
>> And one of the elders answered, saying
unto me, what are these are in white
robes? In which came they? So the
question was who are these people in
these white and where did they come
from? Okay, go ahead and read.
>> And I said unto him, sir, thou knowest.
>> And he said unto me, these are they
which came out of great tribulation.
>> He said, these people came out of great
tribulation. Go ahead.
>> And have washed their robes.
>> And have washed their robes
>> and made them white in the blood of the
lamb.
>> Why you make something white and some
red blood?
We talking spiritually clean.
Spiritually clean
in the blood of the lamb. Which mean
you've been hiding under that blood. How
do you hide under the blood of the lamb?
You keep those commandments. It's really
simple. Nothing complicated about it.
You step outside of those commandments.
You not hiding under the blood of the
lamb.
You're not
I don't care what reason you giving
yourself to do it.
The reasons are in this Bible that you
can do that. And if it's not one of
those, you just out there to your shame
and to your nakedness.
No garments, let alone talking about
clean garments. You have no garments on
if you step outside of doing what say
the Lord God. What verse was that,
>> brother? Go ahead and read.
>> Therefore are they before the throne of
God
>> and serve him day and night in his
temple.
>> Yes.
>> And he that siteth on the throne shall
dwell among them.
>> Yes, sir. Go ahead.
>> They shall hunger no more.
>> Neither thirst anymore. Neither shall
the sun light on them, nor any heat.
>> Go ahead.
>> For the lamb which is in the midst of
the throne shall feed them.
>> Yes.
>> And shall lead them into living
fountains of water.
>> Yes. and God shall wipe away all tears
from their eyes.
>> This is going to be a glorious time,
brothers and sisters, for those who are
blessed to see that time and stand right
there. It's going to be glorious. No
more sickness, no more illness, no more
crying, no more bills in the mail.
Let's go. Revelation 19. You know,
brother, we got them bills in the box.
We worried about
send you one or two. Huh? Revelations
19. Let's start at verse 5. Revelations
19 and five.
Revelation chapter 19. And let's start
in verse five. He said those people
watch their ro in the blood of the lamb.
Okay.
19 and five, brother. 19 and verse 5. Go
ahead and read.
>> And a voice came out of the throne,
saying, "Praise our God, all ye his
servants,
>> and ye that fear him, both small and
great."
>> Yes, sir.
>> And I heard as it were the voice of a
great multitude, and as the voice of
many waters, and as the voice of mighty
thunderings, saying, "Allelujah, for the
Lord God omnipotent reigning."
>> Yes. Let us be glad and rejoice and give
honor to him.
>> For the marriage of the lamb is come
>> and his wife made herself ready.
>> Go ahead, brother.
>> And to her was granted that she should
be arrayed in fine lin and white.
>> So she going to be araid and fine lin
and white. Go ahead.
>> For the fine linen is the righteousness
of saints.
>> You see that's what fine lin
is the righteousness of the saints.
That's what it is. Okay. So, now let's
go to Luke chapter one because we got to
make sure we know what righteousness is.
And we just have five more spots left. I
know I'm up here running my mouth. And
somebody going to tell me I'm moving too
fast.
>> Somebody going to tell me you going too
fast. I keep telling
Luke chapter one because it says the
fine linen is the righteousness of the
saints. We need to find out what
righteousness is and we need to find out
who the saints are. Luke 1 and verse 5.
Go ahead and read it, brother. There was
days of Herod,
>> the king of Judea.
>> Yes.
>> A certain priest named Zacharias.
>> That was John the Baptist dad. Go ahead.
>> Of the course of Abia.
>> Yes.
>> And his wife was of the daughters of
Aaron.
>> That's John the Baptist mother. Go ahead
and read.
>> And her name was Elizabeth.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And they were both righteous before God.
>> They were both what, brother?
>> Righteous before God.
>> Yes.
>> Walking in all the commandments and
ordinances of the Lord. Blameless.
>> See that? They walked in them things
blameless and that's why they were
declared righteous.
So look, so now let's go to second
Timothy 4 because I mentioned Paul
earlier in the lesson. What he said
first Timothy I mean second Timothy 4
because this is something heavy right
here. Brother,
I don't know if I ever be able to say
these words.
Second Timothy 4 verse 5. My brother, go
ahead and read.
>> But watch thou in all things
>> endure afflictions.
>> Yes.
>> Do the work of an evangelist.
>> He said, do the work of an evangelist.
Go ahead and read.
>> Make full proof of thy ministry. make
full proof of your ministry. Go ahead
and read.
>> For I am now ready to be offered.
>> So this brother say he is ready to be
offered.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And the time of my departure is at hand.
>> Go ahead.
>> I have fought a good fight.
>> I have finished my course.
>> Yes.
>> I have kept the faith.
>> Go ahead.
For there is laid up for me a crown of
righteousness, which the Lord, the
righteous judge, shall give me at that
day, and not to me only, but unto all
them also that love his appearance.
>> Do we see how Paul is talking
with brothers and sisters? He's saying,
I know I got a crown laid up for me.
I remember one time I was doing a
lesson. I
judgement was today. Who run if the Lord
walked in this building? I'm starting
judgment right now. Who run up here
first? One brother threw his head.
One brother threw his head up. I was
like,
who is that?
But the thing about it, you have to work
on being ready. You have to work on it
and keep working on it and keep thinking
about it
and you can get yourself. Okay. So now
let's go to uh first John chapter 2. We
start at verse 24.
We have to be prepared for sudden death
for the Lord to come back or whatever
happens we have to be prepared for that
however it rose. First John chapter 2
and let's start at verse 24 my brother.
First John chapter 2 and verse 24. I
mean the this Bible and the writers in
it these guys are writing the same thing
just saying different ways and one of
them a way that one or two of
us something had to stick to us. Okay.
First John chapter 2 verse 24. Go ahead
and read it, brother.
>> Let that therefore abide in you,
>> which ye have heard from the beginning,
>> yes.
>> If that which you have heard from the
beginning shall remain in you, ye also
shall continue in the son and in the
father.
>> He said, you let them from the beginning
abide in you. Hey, you remain in the
father and in the son. Skip down, hit
that verse 28, brother. And now little
children,
>> abide in him that when he shall appear,
>> it says abide in him that when he does
appear, when he ever when he ever decide
to show up, go ahead and read.
>> We may have confidence.
>> We may have what?
>> Confidence.
>> That we may have confidence. Go ahead.
>> And not be ashamed before him at his
coming.
coming. Now, back up and hit that verse
two, my brother. verse verse uh
matter of fact pick it up at verse
three. Verse three. Go ahead and read.
>> And hereby we know that we know him
>> if we keep his commandments.
>> Yes sir.
>> He that said I know him and keepeth not
his commandments is a liar and the truth
is not in him.
>> I mean that's the bar right there
brothers and sisters. I don't care how
holy they talk and how good they dress.
I don't care how the cologne smell it
and how the perfume is smelling.
If you witness them break the
commandments, they do not know the Lord.
They don't know him.
Go ahead and read.
>> But who so keepeth his word?
>> In him verily is the love of God
perfected.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Hereby know we that we are in him.
>> Go ahead. He that said he abideth in him
ought himself al also so to walk even as
he walk.
>> Now see that verse right there go over a
lot of people's head. It says he that
said he abided in him. If you say you
abide in the Lord, it says you should
walk HOW HE WALKED. HOW IS IT THAT YOU
WANT TO WALK IN A DIFFERENT WAY AND SAY
YOU ABIDE IN HIM? HOW IS THAT?
How is it?
Go ahead and read.
I write no new commandment unto you, but
an old commandment which he had from the
beginning.
>> Go ahead.
>> The old commandment is the word which
you have heard from the beginning.
>> That old commandment, that old
commandment, that's the word you heard
from the beginning, even right now, what
they call.
Okay. So, now let's go into Acts chapter
13 because I want y'all to look at
something about David.
Acts 13. And let's go see what David's
greatest asset was. Because we know when
David died, he left Solomon a whole lot
of gold. Millions of dollars worth of
gold.
David was a true servant. He had that
one little slip up
which which encomp about three slip ups
in one.
>> Right. But he had but he had that issue.
Okay. But uh but outside of that the
brother was he was stick to it solid.
Okay. The brother was wealthy. He was a
valiant warrior. He was a great king. He
was a sharp leader.
But let's go find out what his greatest
asset is and was. Okay. Acts 13 and
verse 20. My brother. Go ahead and read
it. And after that he gave unto them
judges
>> about the space of 450 years until
Samuel the prophet.
>> We talking about the Lord. He gave
Israel those judges for those times. And
then Samuel the prophet became one of
his priest. Go ahead and read.
>> And afterward they desired a king.
>> And God gave unto them Saul the son of
six.
>> Yes.
>> A man of the tribe of Benjamin by the
space of 40 years. So he gave them king
Saul when they said hey we want other
human being king we don't want God king
anymore okay go ahead and read and when
he had removed him he raised up unto
them David to be their king
>> to whom also he gave testimony and said
>> I have found David the son of Jesse a
man after mine own heart which shall
fulfill all my will
>> y'all know what you just read
asset was that The Lord testified for
that brother. Do y'all see that God's
approval is the best you could have in
this life? He said God gave testimony
and said, "I have found David, the son
of Jesse, a man after my own heart."
That's his greatest asset right there
was the approval of God. Okay,
that was it. One more verse, brother. of
this man's seed hath God according to
his promise raised unto Israel a savior
Jesus. Yes. Because
Joseph and Mary come out of there. Okay.
All right. So now let's go hit that
Hebrews chapter 11 and then we just have
one more spot after that. Hebrews 11
and6. That was David's greatest asset
and we sitting in there. We hope the
Lord will say that about us. I know we
do.
Well done,
my faithful servant.
We hope the Lord can say something like
that about us.
But if we going to have respect from God
and be able to stand before him and go
eyeball to eyeball with no shame, we
have to be covered in that blood. And
the only way to do that is do what he
told us to do. There's no other way to
do it. There's no other way.
Hebrews 11:6, my brother, go ahead and
read. But without faith, it is
impossible to please him.
>> If you don't believe in him, you can't
please him. Go ahead.
>> For he that cometh to God must believe
that he is.
>> If you come to him, you must believe
that he exist. Go ahead and read. and
that he is a rewarder of them that
diligently seek him.
>> And then you have to believe that he
rewards those that seek him diligently.
Not part time, not halfway, not when
it's convenient for you. Huh?
But that seek him diligently. Okay? He
is a rewarder and you must believe that.
Go ahead and read. By faith, Noah being
warned of God of things not seen as
moved with fear.
>> He moved with what?
>> Fear.
>> Because if you have no fear of God, you
have nothing coming. You got to have
some fear in there. You got to have
some. If you don't have it, you wasting
your time. Okay. Go ahead and read.
>> Moved with fear, prepared an art to the
saving of his house.
>> Yes.
>> By the which he condemned the world, and
became heir of the righteousness which
is by faith.
>> Go ahead.
>> By faith, Abraham when he was called to
go out into a place which he out to
receive for an inheritance obeyed. And
when he went out, not knowing whether he
went
faith in God, you can make moves like
that with no fear.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> By faith he in the land of promise
>> as in a strange country.
>> Yes.
>> Dwelling in tabernacles with Isaac and
Jacob, the heirs with him of the same
promise.
>> Go ahead.
For he looked for a city which hath
foundations, whose builder and maker is
God.
>> If you can't find that city on earth,
not right now. Skip down to 13 and read
that, brother.
>> These all died in faith,
>> not having received the premises.
>> It says, "These all died in faith. They
died in the Lord. They hadn't received
no eternal life yet." Go ahead and read.
>> But having seen them a far off,
>> but they've seen them a far off. Go
ahead. and were persuaded of them.
>> Yes.
>> And embraced them.
>> And confessed that they were strangers
and pilgrims on the earth. I'm telling
y'all, the more you live your life
according to the word of God, you feel
more like a pilgrim on this earth
because you start to feel like only 1%
of the people out here believe this.
Maybe smaller than that. It might be
five of
you feel like it when you look around.
Did you look around on your way driving?
You see how much business was being
conducted?
How many yards was getting cut? Houses
getting painted and built. Huh?
That was verse 13. Skip down to verse 22
and read that. By faith, Joseph when he
died made mention of the departing of
the children of Israel
>> and gave commandment concerning his
bones.
>> Go ahead. By faith, Moses when he was
born was hid three months of his parents
>> because they saw he was a proper child
>> and they were not afraid of the king's
command.
>> So this is faith how these people were
moving. Okay, Joseph had that faith.
Moses parents had that faith. Go ahead
and read, brother.
>> By faith, Moses when he was come two
years refused to be called the son of
Pharaoh's daughter. We all see that when
he refused to be called a grandson of
Pharaoh, the man in charge. Go ahead and
read. Choosing rather to suffer
affliction with the people of God.
>> Choosing rather to suffer affliction as
a slave with the people of God. Go ahead
and read.
pleasures of sin for a season.
>> Y'all see that? He didn't choose the
house of
he
Okay.
What verse was that, brother? Go ahead
and read that 26. You read 26.
>> 26.
>> Go ahead and read. esteeming the
reproach of Christ greater riches than
the treasures in Egypt.
>> I know that's right. Go ahead.
>> For he had respect unto the recompense
of the reward.
>> Skip down to verse 31 and read. We
talking about all these faithful people.
31. Go ahead and read it.
>> By faith the harlot Rahab perish not
with them that believe not.
>> See, she was in a city full of people
that didn't believe, but she her whole
household she saved them because she
believed. Okay, go ahead and read.
>> When she had received the spies with
peace,
>> and what shall I more say? For the time
would fail me to tell of Gideon,
>> of Barack,
>> Yep.
>> of Samson.
>> Yes.
>> And of Jeff,
>> of David also and Samuel and of the
prophets.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Who through faith subdued kingdom.
>> It says through all these people's
faith, they subdued kingdoms. Go ahead
and read.
>> Wrought right.
>> Wrough righteousness. obtain promises.
>> Obtain promises.
>> Stop the m of l.
We talking the Lord did that for Daniel.
Okay, go ahead and read, brother.
>> Quench the violence of fire.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Escape the edge of the sword. Out of
weakness were made strong.
>> Yes.
>> Wax valiant and fight.
>> Turn to flight the armies of the aliens.
>> Skip down to verse 37 and continue.
>> They were stoned.
>> They were stoned. They were s
>> were tempted were slain with the sword.
They wandered about in sheep skins and
goat skins being destitute, afflicted,
tormented.
>> We talking about all these faithful
servants of God. Go ahead and read.
>> Of whom the world was not worthy.
>> Y'all see that? He say the world wasn't
even worthy to have these kind of people
walking around. Y'all see that? Of whom
the world was not worthy. Go ahead and
read, brother. They wondered in deserts
>> and in mountains and in dens and caves
of the earth.
>> Yes.
>> And these all having attained a good
report through faith receive not the
promise.
>> Go ahead.
>> God having provided some better things
for us that they without us should not
be made perfect because everybody's
gonna get that thing at the same time.
Okay. So now let's go to our last place.
Revelation 14. We talking about
preparing to meet your God. Whether he
come up on you in a surprise or whether
you laying on your death bed for 10
months and you know you going to take
that last breath, it doesn't matter.
If your house is in order, Revelations
14, my brother, let's start at verse 12.
Revelations 14 and verse 12. 14 and 12.
Go ahead and read.
>> Here is the patience of the saints.
>> Here's the patience of the saints. And
actually the definition of what a saint
is. Go ahead and read it.
>> Here are they that keep the commandments
of God.
>> That's one side of it. They keep the
commandments of God. Go ahead.
>> And the faith of Jesus.
>> And the faith of Jesus. Go ahead,
brother.
>> And I heard a voice from heaven saying
unto me,
>> right? Blessed are the dead which die in
the Lord. He said, "Blessed are the dead
which die in the Lord." Go ahead,
brother.
>> From hence
>> forth.
>> Yeah. Said the spirit.
>> "That they may rest from their labors."
>> Yes.
>> And their works do follow them.
>> And it said their works do follow them.
The saints, the ones that die in the
Lord. So brothers and sisters,
we get that you can go buy life
insurance today that'll provide for your
family in case we lose you. Okay? But
the best insurance policy that you can
get
is to live in obedience to God. That's
the best kind of insurance policy you
can get out here today. That way it
doesn't matter if death comes up on you
as a surprise or expected or you
standing there waiting on the Lord to
So the best thing to do is prepare your
house, get yourself in order right now,
brothers and sisters, to meet your God.
And I hope somebody was edified with
today's lesson. Thank you for your time.
We got some announcements.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Come Down,
Lord. [music]
Come down.
Come down,
Lord.
Come [music and singing] down.
Come down.
>> [music]